Guide to the Stephen Henry Schneider Papers SC1053
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Print Media, Series 10
  - Climate Stabilization: For Better or for Worse? (SHS and W. W. Kellogg) - Science, 1974 December 17 (Box 198, Folder 63)
  - Climatic Barriers to Long-Term Energy Growth (SHS and Roger D. Dennett) - Ambio, 1975 (Box 198, Folder 64)
  - Energy Production and Climate (SHS and Warren M. Washington) - Science, 1975 January (Box 198, Folder 65)
  - A Convention of Scientists is Headier than Most - The New York Times, 1975 Feb 2 (Box 198, Folder 66)
  - Never Argue Weather with a Groundhog - Town & Country Review, 1975 Feb 5 (Box 198, Folder 67)
  - Tinkering with a Climate Dangerous, Expert Warns - Springfield Leader-Press, 1975 April 2 (Box 198, Folder 68)
  - Responses to Climate Stabilization - Science, 1975 April 18 (Box 198, Folder 69)
  - Everyone Talks About It - UN Television Script, 1975 June 24 (Box 198, Folder 70)
  - Climate and the Global Economy - New Scientist, 1975 Aug 28 (Box 198, Folder 71)
  - Climate and Life [review] - Bulletin American Meteorological Society, 1975 Sept (Box 198, Folder 72)
  - On the Carbon Dioxide - Climate Confusion (SHS) - Journal of Atmospheric Sciences, 1975 Nov (Box 198, Folder 73)
  - Volcanic Dust, Sunspots and Temperature Trends (SHS and Clifford Mass) - Science, 1975 Nov 21 (Box 198, Folder 74)
  - More variable weather threatens world food supply - The Christian Science Monitor, 1975 Dec 9 (Box 198, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence: Glenn English and testimony, 1976 (Box 198, Folder 76)
  - Climate Quote from Frank Herbert's Children of Dune, 1976 (Box 198, Folder 77)
  - Scientist Hopes Groundhog's Right - Town & Country, 1976 Feb 4 (Box 198, Folder 78)
  - The Genesis Strategy (SHS) [excerpt] - Friends of the Earth's Not Man Apart, 1976 March (Box 198, Folder 79)
  - When the Sun went Strangely Quiet - Science News, 1976 March 6 (Box 198, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence: letter from Carl Sagan about a position for SHS at Cornell, 1976 March 23 (Box 198, Folder 81)
  - Mild Winter was Specter of Drought - Town & Country Environmental Edition, 1976 March 31 (Box 198, Folder 82)
  - Global Strategy - The Colorado Daily, 1976 April 6 (Box 198, Folder 83)
  - Forecast: Famine? - Time, 1976 May 17 (Box 198, Folder 84)
  - Climate and Survival - Sierra Club Bulletin, 1976 July/Aug (Box 198, Folder 85)
  - A Hedge Against Famine - Colorado Business Magazine, 1976 July/August (Box 198, Folder 86)
  - Impact of Climatic Fluctuation on Major North American Food Crops, 1976 July (Box 198, Folder 87)
  - A World Praying for Rain - Newsweek, 1976 July 19 (Box 198, Folder 88)
  - The Genesis Strategy: Climate Change & Global Survival (SHS and Lynne E. Mesirow) - The Futurist, 1976 August (Box 198, Folder 89)
  - Wary Climate Threatens the Hungry World - The Dallas Morning News, 1976 Aug 1 (Box 198, Folder 90)
  - Storm over World Weather - Sun Times, 1976 September 12 (Box 198, Folder 91)
  - The Deterioration of the World's Weather - Washington Post, 1976 Oct 10 (Box 198, Folder 92)
  - The Deterioration of the World's Weather - The Washington Post, 1976 Oct 11 (Box 198, Folder 93)
  - Letter from Jimmy Carter [photocopy], 1976 Oct 25 (Box 198, Folder 94)
  - Food-Climate articles from the Saturday Review, 1976 Nov 13 (Box 198, Folder 95)
  - Joseph's Brothers - The Wall Street Journal, 1976 Nov 19 (Box 198, Folder 96)
  - Mosaic, 1977 Jan/Feb (Box 198, Folder 97)
  - Drought Perils 13 Western States and TV: Can Sunspots Tan Bionic Angel? - The New York Times, 1977 Feb 2 (Box 198, Folder 98)
  - Is the Drought Here to Stay? - The Straight Creek, 1977 March 10 (Box 198, Folder 99)
  - Weather - how will it affect you? - Harvestore Farmer, 1977 April (Box 198, Folder 100)
  - Who's Who Volume I, Broadcast 15 - Rosalynn Carter, Lily Tomlin, SHS, Dave Garroway, Billy the Bugler, 1977 April 26 (Box 198, Folder 101)
  - draft Review of The Weather Conspiracy, 1977 May 16 (Box 198, Folder 102)
  - Correspondence with August Sebastiani (vineyards), 1977 October 3 (Box 198, Folder 103)
  - Bad Weather Ahead? Plan On It - Rocky Mountain News, 1977 October 30 (Box 198, Folder 104)
  - NCAR wunderkind mocks prophet reputation, stresses a world food situation - The Colorado Daily, 1977 Nov 4 (Box 198, Folder 105)
  - Correspondence: letter from Dad about scientists and media, 1977 December 5 (Box 198, Folder 106)
  - No disastrous change in climate by 2000? - SF Sunday Examiner and Chronicle, 1978 Feb 26 (Box 198, Folder 107)
  - The human factor in modifying the weather - Business Week, 1978 Feb 27 (Box 198, Folder 108)
  - So What if the Climate Changes? (SHS) AAS annual meeting, Houston, 1979 January (Box 198, Folder 109)
  - Scientists Forecast World Warming, Coastal Floods - Denver Post, 1979 January (Box 198, Folder 110)
  - Article re: rain dance @ Mt. Tamalpais and drought, 1977 February 22 (Box 223, Folder 1)
  - United Nations Development Forum news clippings, 1976-1979 (Box 241, Item 1-3)
  - clippings/copies [annotated], (notes for "The Genesis Strategy" ?) (Box 241, Folder 4)
  - clippings/copies [annotated] on index cards (Box 241, Folder 5)
  - New York Times Book Review [The Genesis Strategy], July 18, 1976 (Box 241, Folder 6)
  - clippings from Henry Lamsford (Box 241, Folder 7)
  - 17 NCAR envelopes of clippings [many with SHS annotations] (Box 241, Item 8-24)
  - 3 copies of a poster for a lecture given by SHS at Fermilab, 1977 (Box 241, Folder 25)
  - Press Clippings, 1974-1991 (Box 246, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 246, Folder 16)
  - The Planet, 2005 Sept/Oct (Box 246, Folder 17)
  - Article in Sonntags Zeitung, 1995 (Box 246, Folder 18)
  - Extinction of the fittest may be the legacy of lost habitats - New York Times, 1994 Sept 27 (Box 246, Folder 19)
  - "Volcano" Interview, 2007 (Box 246, Folder 20)
  - Suzy Chaffee "Abundant Snow", 2008 (Box 246, Folder 21)
  - The Scientist - Research - Global Warming Researchers Say They Need Breathing Room, 1992 May 11 (Box 246, Folder 22)
  - National Geographic - Is our World Warming? Under the Sun, 1990 October (Box 246, Folder 23)
  - The Heat is On, 1987 Oct 19 (Box 246, Folder 24)
  - In Future - Opening Night, 1988 Dec 11 (Box 246, Folder 25)
  - Aera Weekly - Japanese Magazine, 1989 Aug 25 (Box 246, Folder 26)
  - Esquire Magazine Clipping and Reader's Digest, 1989 (Box 246, Folder 27)
  - Discover Magazine - The Greenhouse Effect, 1988 October (Box 246, Folder 28)
  - Audubon Magazine - Gazing into our Greenhouse Future, 1991 March (Box 246, Folder 29)
  - Defender of the Planet - News Article, 1988 May 15 (Box 246, Folder 30)
  - Press: SHS, 1989-1993 (Box 246, Folder 31)
  - The Stanford Daily - Global Climate Change and the Politics of Risk, 1995 May 9 (Box 246, Folder 32)
  - ESIG Newsletter - NCAR, 1986 Sept 27 (Box 246, Folder 33)
  - Los Angeles Times Book Review, "Natural Havoc by Human Hand: The Coevolution of Climate and Life", 1984 August 5 (Box 250, Folder 8)
  - The New York Times Book Review, p44, 1984 December 2 (Box 250, Folder 9)
  - The New York Times Book Review, p11, 1984 August 19 (Box 250, Folder 10)
  - La Jolla Courier, "Red China: A Cultural Revolution", 1974 June 20 (Box 250, Folder 11)
  - The National Observer, "It's Only Superstition, Right?", 1974 June 1 (Box 250, Folder 12)
  - The Denver Post, "Droughts Raise Food-Crisis Fears", 1974 June 9 (Box 250, Folder 13)
  - Quest: The San Diego Union-Tribune, "Plants May Be Key to Curbing Global Warming: Seeds of a Solution", 1996 February 28 (Box 250, Folder 14)
  - The Burlington Free Press, "Can We Stop the Warming? Quick Action Would Slow Global Trend, Experts Say", 1996 April 22 (Box 250, Folder 15)
  - Rocky Mountain News: Sunday Magazine, "Defender of the Planet: Climatologist Stephen Schneider", 1988 May 15 (Box 250, Folder 16)
- Photographs, Series 11
  - Lantern Slides
    - Outline of the Finite Different Scheme (Box 176, Item 1)
    - Charts for Shock Speed & Aritical Viscosity Only (Box 176, Item 2)
    - Hydrogen Shock Struture, B_lθ=7KG (Box 176, Item 3)
    - Jaffrin_Probstein Solution & Numerical Solution (Box 176, Item 4)
    - Shock Speed Comparison (Box 176, Item 5)
    - Transverse MHD Shock Wave & Drive-Current Layer (Box 176, Item 6)
    - Hydrogen Shock Structure, B = 0 (Box 176, Item 7)
    - Two-Temperature Navier-Strokes Equations (Box 176, Item 8)
    - Gas Shock Wave & Drive-Current Layer (Box 176, Item 9)
    - B(t)_a & B(t)_b Chart (Box 176, Item 10)
    - Shock Thickness vs. Shock Speed (Box 176, Item 11)
    - B(t)_a & B(t)_b Chart, U_S=95cm/µsec (Box 176, Item 12)
    - Temperature (Electronic Volts) & Shock Speed (Box 176, Item 13)
    - X-Ray Data (Box 176, Item 14)
    - Partition of Energy & U_s (cm/µsec) (Box 176, Item 15)
    - l(cm) & U_s (cm/µsec) (Box 176, Item 16)
    - Current-sheet & Shock-wave Trajectories (Box 176, Item 17)
    - Time-Distance Diagrams of Computed Results for Transverse MHD Case w/o Initial Bias (Box 176, Item 18)
    - 'Starting' Numerical Dissipation (Box 176, Item 19)
    - Diagram of the Inner & Outer Conductor (Box 176, Item 20)
    - The Lundquist Equations in Lagrangian Coordinates in Conservation Form (Box 176, Item 21)
    - "Saturated" Shock Graph (Box 176, Item 22)
    - B(t)_a & B(t)_b Contact Surface Graph (Box 176, Item 23)
    - Initial Oscillations Graph & Solid Piston Driven Transverse Shock Wave Graph (Box 176, Item 24)
  - Photographic slides
    - Photographic Slides: Travel (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - Photographic Slides: Art Slides w/ Karen Kucharski (Box 158, Folder 2)
    - Photographic Slides: David Hiser (Box 158, Folder 3)
    - Photographic Slides: World Temperatures (Box 158, Folder 5)
    - Photographic Slides: Travel/Camping/Mountains (Box 158, Folder 6)
    - Photographic Slides: Travel/Terry Root (Box 158, Folder 7)
    - Photographic Slides: Great Basin- N.Park/Hiking/Travel (Box 158, Folder 8)
    - Photographic Slides: Travel/Hawaii/Great Lake (Box 158, Folder 9)
    - Photographic Slides: Duplicates - Nuclear War/Climate (Box 158, Folder 10)
    - Photographic Slides: CCM Results w/Smoke IR & Scattering (Box 158, Folder 11)
    - Photographic Slides: "Paleo" Dust Presentation (Box 158, Folder 12)
    - Photographic Slides: CO2 Presentation/Duplicates (Box 158, Folder 13)
    - Photographic Slides: Originals from SLT DNA Meeting (Box 158, Folder 14)
    - Photographic Slides: Originals from SLT DNA Meeting (Box 158, Folder 15)
    - Photographic Slides: CO2 Presentation, Magazine Articles, Duplicates (Box 158, Folder 16)
    - Photographic Slides: CO2 Presentation, Articles, Explosion Population (Box 158, Folder 17)
    - Photographic Slides: Greenhouse Effect, Travel, Holland Herald (Box 158, Folder 18)
    - Photographic Slides: Nature, Climatic Research, Temperature Research (Box 158, Folder 19)
    - Photographic Slides: Originals, Travel, Asia, Desert, Mountains, Fields (Box 158, Folder 20)
    - Photographic Slides: Great Basin, Travel, Alternative Energy, Duplicates (Box 158, Folder 21)
    - Photographic Slides: Hawaii, Travel (Box 158, Folder 22)
    - Photographic Slides: Nuclear Winter, Duplicates (Box 158, Folder 23)
    - Photographic Slides: Presentation Styles, Climatic Research (Box 158, Folder 24)
    - Photographic Slides: Pettston, Bio St. Am, Maine, Travel (Box 158, Folder 25)
    - Photographic Slides: Climatic Research, Temperature Research, Travel (Box 158, Folder 26)
    - Photographic Slides: Nuclear Winter (Box 158, Folder 27)
    - Photographic Slides: Colorado, Travel (Box 158, Folder 28)
    - Photographic Slides: N. Power Room, Snow, Travel, Polar Bears (Box 158, Folder 29)
    - Photographic Slides: Times Magazine, Greenhouse Effect, Travel (Box 158, Folder 30)
    - Photographic Slides: Great Basin, Hiking, Travel, Research, Building Hours (Box 158, Folder 31)
    - Photographic Slides: Travel, CO2 Presentation, Mountains, Snow, Forests (Box 158, Folder 32)
    - Photographic Slides: Duplicates, Climate Research, Temperature Research (Box 158, Folder 33)
    - Photographic Slides: Energy Efficiency, Temperature Research, Duplicates (Box 158, Folder 34)
    - Photographic Slides: Global Warming, Greenhouse Effect (Box 158, Folder 35)
    - Photographic Slides: Energy Efficiency, Climatic Research, Conserving Energy (Box 158, Folder 36)
    - Photographic Slides: "Nuke Winter" I (Box 158, Folder 37)
    - Photographic Slides: "Nuke Winter" II (Box 158, Folder 38)
    - Photographic Slides: Climatic Research, Global Warming, Seldom Used (Box 158, Folder 39)
    - Photographic Slides: Food Comsumption, Energy Efficiency, Asia, Travel (Box 158, Folder 40)
    - Photographic Slides: Originals, SLT, Ames DNA Meeting (Box 158, Folder 41)
    - Photographic Slides: Israel 3 - Travel, Smyrva Kisher, Bouellis' Eagle Nest (Box 158, Folder 42)
    - Photographic Slides: Israel 4 - Bouellis' Eagle Nest, Metgugie, Burda Minet, Wei Tzmann, Solon Tower (Box 158, Folder 43)
    - Photographic Slides: Israel 2 - Ruffet W.R. at Eliat, Guide Plaingos, Aquaba Coal, Planrin, Saudi Arabia (Box 158, Folder 44)
    - Photographic Slides: Israel 1 - Hollow Wind, Turbine, Blacktabe Bogent, Geese, Diker, Ruven Yousef, Ringing Station (Box 158, Folder 45)
    - Photographic Slides: Israel 5 - Wei Tzmann, Solar Tower, Scops Owl, Iber, Sede Roger (Box 158, Folder 46)
    - Photographic Slides: Hawaii, Travel, Sea, Mountains, Beaches, Forests (Box 158, Folder 47)
    - Photographic Slides: Underground Caverns, Power Plants, Travel, Climatic Research (Box 158, Folder 48)
    - Photographic Slides: Duplicates, Northern Hemisphere, Mountains, Travel (Box 158, Folder 49)
    - Photographic Slides: CO2, Notes, Graphs, Charts, Temperature Research (Box 158, Folder 50)
    - Photographic Slides: Climatic Research, Temperature Research, Duplicates, Water Cycles (Box 158, Folder 51)
    - Photographic Slides: Acpulco, Guevero National Park Travel, Hiking, Sea, Mountains (Box 158, Folder 52)
    - Photographic Slides: Plants, Gardens, Bear Coal Co, Inc., AWMU, Travel (Box 158, Folder 53)
    - Photographic Slides (Box 158, Folder 54)
    - Photographic Slides: Plants, Animals, Research, Travel, Duplicates (Box 158, Folder 55)
    - Photographic Slides (Box 158, Folder 56)
    - Photographic Slides (Box 158, Folder 57)
    - Photographic Slides (Box 158, Folder 58)
    - Photographic Slides: Denali, Travel (Box 158, Folder 59)
    - Photographic Slides: Pipeline, Denali, Travel (Box 158, Folder 60)
    - Photographic Slides: Cartoon Duplicates, includes printed cartoons (Box 158, Folder 61)
    - Photographic Slides: Climate Change, Maps, Charts, includes Calendar (Box 158, Folder 62)
    - Photographic Slides: Climate Change, Charts (Box 158, Folder 63)
    - Photographic Slides: Climate Change (Box 158, Folder 64)
    - Photographic Slides: Climate Change, Maps, Charts (Box 158, Folder 65)
    - Photographic Slides: Climate Change (Box 158, Folder 66)
    - Photographic Slides: Primlof Cliff, Coastal Birds, Travel (Box 158, Folder 67)
    - Photographic Slides: Primlof Cliffs, Coastal Birds, Bird Watching (Box 158, Folder 68)
    - Photographic Slides: Primlof Cliffs, Outtakes, Too Dark (Box 158, Folder 69)
    - Photographic Slides: Travel, Muldhow Glacier, Denali River, Wildlife (Box 158, Folder 70)
    - Photographic Slides: Portage Glacier, Alaska, Travel, Wildlife (Box 158, Folder 71)
    - Photographic Slides: S.E. Alaska, St. Paul Island, Priblofs #1, Wildlife (Box 158, Folder 72)
    - Photographic Slides: Anchorage - Alaska, Denali #6, Wildlife, Travel (Box 158, Folder 73)
    - Photographic Slides: Primlof Cliffs, Seals, Artic Fox, Wildlife (Box 158, Folder 74)
    - Photographic Slides: Alaska, Seals, Coastal Birds, Bird Watching (Box 158, Folder 75)
    - Photographic Slides: Polar Bears, Alaska, Travel (Box 158, Folder 76)
    - Photographic Slides: Travel, Arctic Valley, Alaska Wildlife, Denali, Mt. Rushmore, Arizona (Box 158, Folder 77)
  - Negatives: Experiments, Greenhouse Effect, Data, Graphs (Box 177, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Experiments, Greenhouse Effect, Data, Graphs (Box 177, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Portraits of Schneider (Box 177, Folder 3)
  - Photographic Slides: Schneider's House being Built (Box 177, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Graphs & Charts (Box 177, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Schneider Office Comics (Box 177, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: Great Photos of Schneider (Box 177, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: Photos of Schneider (Box 177, Folder 8)
  - Photographs & Photographic Slides: Photos of Schneider (Box 177, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Photos of Schneider (Box 177, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: Photos of Schneider (Box 177, Folder 11)
  - snapshots from Europe (?) (Box 247, Folder 12)
  - Photographs & Photographic Slides: Photos of Schneider (Box 177, Folder 13)
  - negatives (Box 247, Folder 14)
  - photographic reprints (Box 247, Folder 15)
  - Photographs & Negatives: Photos of Schneider (Box 177, Folder 16)
- Audiovisual Material, Series 12
  - Too Hot to Handle: Global Warming is the Most Urgent Threat Facing Humanity Today (Box 146, Item 1)
  - The Baltic: A Sea of Peril (Box 146, Item 2)
  - The Green Patriarch (Box 146, Item 3)
  - The Adriatic: A Sea at Risk, 6/11/2002 (Box 146, Item 4)
  - The Artic: The Consequences of Human Folly, 2007 Sep 7 (Box 146, Item 5)
  - The Amazon: The End of Infinity (Box 146, Item 6)
  - The Black Sea: A Voyage of Healing (Box 146, Item 7)
  - Culivating Sustainability: The Copenhegan COP15 Experience (Box 146, Item 8)
  - Perfect Balance (Box 146, Item 9)
  - The ARK Video (Box 146, Item 10)
  - Where the Rubber Meets the Road, circa 1990's (Box 146, Item 11)
  - "Quark" & "5 Ipotesi Sulla Fine Del Mondo" (Theories on the End of the World), 1983-1985 (Box 146, Item 12)
  - California Got it Wrong Texas Got it Right (Box 146, Item 13)
  - USIA Talk Show/ "Greenhouse Effect"/ Stephen Schneider, Patrick Zimmerman, and Anthony Sligo, 6/1/1989 (Box 146, Item 14)
  - Nova - Goddess of the Earth, circa 1986 (Box 146, Item 15)
  - Nova - Climate Crisis: The Greenhouse Effect, Dec. 1983 (Box 146, Item 16)
  - Nuclear Winter - Ethics of Dispute (Box 146, Item 17)
  - Nova - Warming Warning, circa 1983 (Box 146, Item 18)
  - "How About…" Science Mini-features for Television: 11 Shows (with Introductions) (Box 146, Item 19)
  - Computer Animations from the GENESIS: Earth System Modeling Project, circa 1995; AV videotape 23 deaccessioned from this box. (Box 147, Item 20)
  - The Powers of Ten in Time - Phase 2 Prototype Demo, 10/24/1993 (Box 147, Item 21)
  - The Powers of Ten in Time - Phase 1 Prototype Demo, 4/4/1993 (Box 147, Item 22)
  - Department of Cardiovascular Surgery: Grand Rounds/ Global Warming: Scientific Fact or Media Hype presented by Stephen Schneider/ CNN Future With HCIT, 1989-1990 (Box 147, Item 24)
  - Ketchum Public Relations: Crisis in the Atmosphere (Box 147, Item 25)
  - Network Earth Show #31, March 1991 (Box 147, Item 26)
  - Enviormental Media Awards, circa 1990's (Box 147, Item 27)
  - National Geographic Society: Diversity of Lfie (Box 147, Item 28)
  - Chevron Corporation, Parkins/Baldwin - EcoSpeak: Coming to An Understanding\ The Greenhouse Effect Rev. 2 (Box 147, Item 29)
  - Vanishing Lands (Box 147, Item 30)
  - 2 (Box 147, Item 31)
  - No Title (Box 147, Item 32)
  - Steve - Ch 13: Crisis in the Atmosphere, 11/29/1989 (Box 147, Item 33)
  - Indiana Jones (Box 147, Item 34)
  - Nova - Hole in the Ozone/ Nova - On Kistiakowsky (with Segon)/ Nova - Desert/ Nova - S. J. Gould, circa 1987 (Box 147, Item 35)
  - CNN Earth Matters (IPCC Debate), 9/1/1996 (Box 147, Item 36)
  - Walter Cronkite at Large, 6/11/1988 (Box 147, Item 37)
  - Ozone Depletion, 10/30/1986 (Box 147, Item 38)
  - Nightline on Contrarian (with Stephen Schneider), 1994 Feb 24 (Box 147, Item 39)
  - Nuclear Winter: Ethics of Dispute (CP)/ Meche/OppNishtteo O2/motes Jess L/ ABC Pollrim, 1987-1988 (Box 147, Item 40)
  - Nuclear Winter: Ethics of Dispute (Box 147, Item 41)
  - Nuclear Winter: Ethics of Dispute (Box 147, Item 42)
  - Nuclear Winter: Ethics of Dispute (Box 147, Item 43)
  - Dateline - Sonya Crawford/ Nature's Wrath, 2/26/1997 (Box 147, Item 44)
  - Nuclear Winter: First Rough (Box 147, Item 45)
  - Nuclear Winter: Round Table - Cut Down Number 1/ Stephen H. Schneider - 1976 (Winter), circa 1976 (Box 147, Item 46)
  - Yucca Mtn. ICS @ NCAR (Box 147, Item 47)
  - "2010" (Box 147, Item 48)
  - Steve Schneider's Austrialia Video, Oct. & Nov. 1988 (Box 147, Item 49)
  - SHS on Discover Magazine "Weather", 5/14/1997 (Box 147, Item 50)
  - Nuclear Winter, AV videotapes 61, 72-83, 88, and 94, deaccessioned from this box. (Box 148, Item 51)
  - Nova - "A. Rain"/ Nuclear Winter - Nightline (Box 148, Item 52)
  - Nuclear Winter - Group Discussion - 3 Cameras (Box 148, Item 53)
  - Sagan Lecture/ SHS Rough on Shdis segment (Box 148, Item 54)
  - Plane T Earth/ NOS: 1, 2, & 3 (SHS & EJB) (Box 148, Item 55)
  - ABC's "The Day After" & View point (Box 148, Item 56)
  - SHS on NBC Magazine/ SHS on Nightline/ Interview by Bazillon TODAY Show, 1981-1986 (Box 148, Item 57)
  - Nuclear Winter - Walter Orr Roberts Camera (Box 148, Item 58)
  - Planet Earth Nos. 4, 5, 6, & 7 (Box 148, Item 59)
  - Body In Question (Dudley)/ Nova - Climate (SHS Showing)/ Nova - Goddess of Earth (Box 148, Item 60)
  - SHS on "State of Colorado"/ Chernobyl TMI, 1985 (Box 148, Item 62)
  - Beverly Hills Cop/ Nuclear Winter: Ethics of Dispute (Box 148, Item 63)
  - Chernobyl US/USSR, 9/11/1988 (Box 148, Item 64)
  - Life on Earth IX, X, & XI (Box 148, Item 65)
  - Life on Earth XII & XIII (Box 148, Item 66)
  - Life on Earth VI, VII, VIII (Box 148, Item 67)
  - Cosmos "The Edge of Torae"/ Nova - Calvarez Asteroid Theory (Box 148, Item 68)
  - Oceanside Baseball/ Pool Antics, 7/4/1987 (Box 148, Item 69)
  - Life on Earth I & II (Box 148, Item 70)
  - Life on Earth III, IV, & V (Box 148, Item 71)
  - Hard Chores (6 programs) (Box 148, Item 84)
  - Nova - The Sunspot Mystery 1978 Version (Box 148, Item 85)
  - The Today Show/ The State of Colorado/ Healthier Babies- The Genetic Era, 9/24/1982 (Box 148, Item 86)
  - Carson\2d/ Rewind Problem, 1977-1978 (Box 148, Item 87)
  - IPBN Presents Mary Jane Odell, Guest: Stephen Schneider (Box 148, Item 89)
  - Fueling the Future: No Deposit - No Return, 1988 (Box 148, Item 90)
  - "Take Issues" Bay-TV Talk Show/ CBS News w/ Dan Rather - Geoengineering/ CBS News w/ Dan Rather - Tornado Mwanes/ Tupe defective, 1998-2001 (Box 148, Item 91)
  - State of the Planet - Program 3 - The Future of Life, 1977 (Box 148, Item 92)
  - SHS on CBS News w/ Dan Rather/ SHS Archives: Who's Who (Rather) & Larson Show, 1977 & 2001 (Box 148, Item 93)
  - Body in Question (Box 148, Item 95)
  - ABC View Point (Press)/ Moyers et al, 1/22/1982 (Box 148, Item 96)
  - 8 - Kirshner/ Suader/ Abram (Box 154, Item 254)
  - Men & Molecules - Hel Ben. Steel (Box 154, Item 255)
  - Men & Molecules - Come Rain, Come Shine II (Box 154, Item 256)
  - KOA Special Report - "Weather" (Box 154, Item 257)
  - Perle, Wirth, Turco, Los Alamos Film - World Conference and Sagan at Boettcher (Box 154, Item 258)
  - Exxon Research Club/ The Lory Holwin Winter, 1989 (Box 154, Item 259)
  - Science Video Newsreel/ Science & Television Retreat, 1987 (Box 154, Item 260)
  - Future Watch/ Steve's Future House (Box 154, Item 261)
  - Endangered Earth (Box 154, Item 262)
  - Australian Broadcasting Corp. - "Quantum" Special program & "Greenhouse Effect", 11/2/1988 (Box 154, Item 263)
  - Colloquim - "Future Climate Change" - Dub, 1987 Mar 16 (Box 154, Item 264)
  - The Search for Solutions Series: Investigation, Evidence, Patterns, Modeling, Theory, Practice, Adaptation, Context, Trial & Error (Box 154, Item 265)
  - The Challenge of the Unknown/ Part I - Situation/ Part II - Outcomes (Box 154, Item 266)